Business and Professional Women's Club of Schenectady; Records apap218
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Business and Professional Women's Clubs of Schenectady, New York Records
1927-2011, Undated
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap218
19.42 cubic ft.
These records document the history of the Business and Professional Women's Club of Schenectady, NY.
Collection X
Biographical History
The Schenectady Business and Professional Women's Club was federated on May 11, 1927 at what is now Schenectady County Community College. Founded on July 15, 1919, the Business and Professional Women's Club was financed through a federal grant established by the War Department to help professional women organizations. According to its vision statement it strives to be "the premier organization of women serving women...an active and inclusive club that fosters economic self-sufficiency, professional mentorship and resources, and a diverse network of members supporting each other, the community and those new to the area." There were 51 charter members, and Ella Magill Talbot served as the first president of the organization. In 1936, the Schenectady Club became incorporated into the New York State, National, and International Federations of Business and Professional Women's Clubs.
Currently the Schenectady Business and Professional Women's Club holds monthly meetings where members, "grow professionally, explore career strategies, and advocate for women regarding important social issues." The Business and Professional Women's Club also helps promote the elimination of gender discrimination in employment and equal pay. Some of the events that the Club hosts include, a fashion show, guest speakers, and a celebration of the woman of the year from their membership. The Club also offers scholarships to women who are high school seniors in Schenectady County and women over twenty-five who are returning to their studies to promote women in their pursuit to receive a higher education.
Scope and Contents
These records document the history of the Business and Professional Women's (BPW) Club of Schenectady, NY. The collection includes financial documents, meeting minutes, news clippings, publications, events and programs, scrapbooks detailing the Club's activities and accomplishments, and photographs. The collection also includes records retained by Club members involved in BPW activities at the district and state levels.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Acquisition Information
Members Judy Schultz, Jean Osterhout, and Catherine Raycroft donated materials for the collection in a series of four accessions in 2006-2007.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Education; Women; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Schenectady, New York; Businesswomen--New York (State)
- Administrative, 1927-2005, Undated; 1; 4.79 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of audits, budgets, by-laws, expense reports, meeting minutes, anniversary proclamations, and files of the president, secretary, and treasurer. Membership lists, rosters, and directories are also included in the series.
  - Annual President Reports, 1927-1951; 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - BPW Club Treasurer Guidelines, 1982; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - BPW President, 1985; 1990; 1994-1995; 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brochures, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - By-Laws, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - By-Laws, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - By-Laws, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - By-Laws, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - By-Laws, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - By-Laws, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - By-Laws, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - By-Laws, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - By-Laws, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - By-Laws, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - By-Laws, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - By-Laws, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - By-Laws, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - By-Laws, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - By-Laws and Constitution, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1997 (Flat-file 1)
  - Charter, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Committees, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Coreta V. Hatlee Endowment Fund, 1983; 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Expense Receipts, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Financials, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Financials, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Financials, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Financials, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Financials, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Financials, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Financials, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Financials, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Financials, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Financials, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Financials, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Financials, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Financials, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Financials, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Financials, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Financials, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Financials, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Financials, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Financials, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Financials, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Financials, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Financials, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Financials, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Financials, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Financials, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Financials, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Financials, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Financials, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Financials, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Foundation Vice Chair Files, 1995; 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Handbook of Policies and Procedures, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Handbook of Policies and Procedures, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - How to Have A Good Meeting, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Judith Schultz Files, 1993; 1996-1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Linda Veraska Secretary Files (1 of 2), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Linda Veraska Secretary Files (2 of 2), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Local Organization Action Planner, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Local Organization President and Officers, 1979; 1991-1992; 1998; Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Manual of Instruction (1 of 2), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Manual of Instruction (2 of 2), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Minutes (1 of 3), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Minutes (2 of 3), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Minutes (3 of 3), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Minutes (1 of 4), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Minutes (2 of 4), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Minutes (3 of 4), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Minutes (4 of 4), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Minutes (1 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Minutes (2 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Meeting Minutes (3 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Minutes (4 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Minutes (5 of 5), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Meeting Minutes (1 of 4), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes (2 of 4), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Minutes (3 of 4), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Minutes (4 of 4), 2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Minutes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Model Local Organization By-Laws, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Nominating Committee, 1971-1979; 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Organization Pamphlet, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Parliamentary Procedure, 1974-1975; 1980; 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - President Charlotte George's Files, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - President Charlotte George's Files, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - President Margaret A. Smith's Files, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Presidents Packet, 1997; Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Proclamations, 1970; 1972-1973; 1987; 1994; 2002-2003 (Flat-file 2)
  - Secretary Board Minutes, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - State Citations, 1992 (Flat-file 3)
  - State Citations, 1997 (Flat-file 4)
  - State Directory, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Stationery, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Treasurer Audit, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Treasurer Audit (1 of 2), 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Treasurer Audit (2 of 2), 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Treasurer Files, 1969; 1978; 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Treasurer Ledger, 1926-1936 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Treasurer Ledger, 1937-1941 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Treasurer Pins, 2003 (Oversized 1)
  - Website, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Events and Programs, 1947-2006, Undated; 2; 3.35 cubic ft.
  This series consists of materials detailing the events and the educational programs held by the organization. Materials included are bound programs, handbills, leaflets, pamphlets, photographs, and manuals. Various folders hold documents related to the series during a single year or a span of years, while other folders hold specific events or programs held during consecutive years. Some events or programs were held in succession for many years by the organization, such as the Woman of the Year Award, Young Careerist Award, the Annual Fashion Show, the Legislative Platform Program, and the Issues Management Program. A unique fundraising program entitled "Save the Satchel" during 1999-2000 raised money to support the conservation of Susan B. Anthony's alligator satchel. The Business and Professional Women's Club of Schenectady also collaborated with other clubs to hold events such as the 2001 Business and Professional Women's Club of Schenectady and Kiwanis Art Show. Annual conferences and anniversary celebrations are also included in the series.
  - 20th Anniversary, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 40th Anniversary Dinner, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 50th Anniversary, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 70th Anniversary Celebration, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 75th Anniversary, Ad Forms, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 75th Anniversary Committee (1 of 2), 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 76th Anniversary Committee (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BPWS and Kiwanis Club Art Auction, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Building Women Power, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Business Woman's Trade Show, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Emblem Program, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Equal Pay, 1973; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Events, 1973; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Events, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Events, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Events, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Events, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Events, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Events, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Events, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Events, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Events, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Events, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Events, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Events, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Events, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Events, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Events, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Events, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Events, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Events, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Events, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Events, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Events, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fashion Show, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fashion Show, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fashion Show, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fashion Show, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fashion Show, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fashion Show, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fashion Show, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fashion Show Programs, 1991-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Former Member and Leadership, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Foundation, 1981-1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Girl Scouts Collaboration (1 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Girl Scouts Collaboration (2 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Green Knitted Coaster, Undated
  - Individual Development Program, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Individual Development Program, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Issues Management, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Legislative, 1974-1975; 1977; 1985; 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Legislative (1 of 2), 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Legislative (2 of 2), 1993-1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Legislative, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Platform Program, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - National Committee on Pay Equity, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Save the Satchel Project (1 of 3), 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Save the Satchel Project (2 of 3), 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Save the Satchel Project (3 of 3), 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Scholarship, 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Social Security Program, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speakers, 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Speech Training, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - State Lobby Day, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Status of Women, 1985; 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Train the Trainer Effective Leaders, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Woman Of The Year, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Woman Of The Year, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Woman Of The Year, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Woman Of The Year, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Women and the Workplace 2nd Annual Conference, 1982; 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Women's History Month (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Women's History Month (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Women In The Military, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wooden Collect Table Topper, Undated
  - Young Careerist Program, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Young Careerist Program, 1983; 1985; 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Young Careerist Program, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Young Careerist Program, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Youth Leadership, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Youth Leadership, 1992-1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Subject Files, 1938-2005, Undated; 3; 1.21 cubic ft.
  The Subject Files series contains newspaper clippings, photographs, correspondence, other Business and Professional Women's Club newsletters, publicity scrapbooks and public relations documents, awards and certificates, club dinner invitations from the 1970s, club poems, a 2001 club calendar, and membership records.
  - 2001 Calendar (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 50th Anniversary Program, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1943-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1991; 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1994; 2002-2004 (Flat-file 5)
  - Awards and Certificates, 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BPW/NYS Directory, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BPW/NYS Directory, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - BPW/NYS Leadership Directory, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1997; 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dinner Invitations, 1975; 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Glee Club Membership, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Guidelines for Local Organization News Service, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Member Listing, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Member Listing, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Member Listing, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Member Listing, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Member Listing, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Member Listing, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Member Listing, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Member Listing, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Member Listing, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Member Listing, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Member Listing, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Member Roster BPW/USA, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Membership, Annual Hospitality Report, 1994-1996; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Membership, Annual Report, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Membership, General, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Membership, General, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Membership, General, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Membership, General, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Membership, General, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Membership, General, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Membership, General, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Membership, General, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Membership, General, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Membership, General, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Membership, General, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Membership, General, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Membership, General, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Membership, General, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Membership, General, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Membership, General, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Membership, General, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Membership, General, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Membership, General, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Membership, General, Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Networking Directory, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1952; 1972-1973; 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Other Club Newsletters, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Other Club Newsletters, 1990-1992; 1994-1998; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Past Presidents, 1927-2002 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Photographs, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Photographs, circa. 1950; 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Photographs, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Photographs, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Photographs, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Photographs, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Poems, 1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Press Release, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Promotional Folder, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Public Relations, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Public Relations, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Public Relations, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Public Relations, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Public Relations, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Public Relations, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Public Relations Kit, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Public Relations Kit Cassette Tape, 1991 (Oversized 1)
  - Public Relations Report, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Publicity, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Publicity Scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Rosters (1 of 3), 1979-2002 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Rosters (2 of 3), 1979-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rosters (3 of 3), 1979-2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Speak-Up - Join BPW, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer of Memberships Files, 1981-1984; 1989-1990; 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Publications, 1933-2011; 4; 1.0 cubic ft.
  The Publications series consists of two publications. One is The Handclasp, a monthly newsletter published by the Business and Professional Women's Club of Schenectady (1932-2011, with gaps), and the other is The Communicator, a monthly newsletter published by the Business and Professional Women's Club of New York State (2001-2003, with gaps).
  - The Communicator (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Communicator (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Communicator (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Handclasp (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Handclasp (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Handclasp (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Club History, 1927-2003, Undated; 5; 4.32 cubic ft.
  This series consists of scrapbooks created by previous presidents and members of the Business and Professional Women's Club of Schenectady, photographs of members at various events, club highlights, and highlights in the history of the club.
  - 60 Years of BPW, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 60th Anniversary, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 60th Anniversary Party Slides, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 65th Anniversary, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A History of the National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs Inc., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)